<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ReScience C</title>
    <description>Reproducible Science is good.&lt;br/&gt; Replicated Science is better.</description>
    <link>http://rescience.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rescience.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 12:02:18 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 12:02:18 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>ReScience (R)evolution</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Four years ago, we launched ReScience, a new scientific journal aimed at
publishing the replication of existing computational research. Since ReScience
published its first article, things have been going steadily. We are still
alive, independent and without a budget. In the meantime, we have published
around 25 articles and the initial has grown from around 10 to roughly 100
members (editors and reviewers), we have advertised ReScience at several
conferences worldwide, gave some interviews, and published an article
introducing ReScience in PeerJ Computer Sience. Based on our experience at
managing the journal during these four years, we thought that time was ripe for
some changes. Read our
&lt;a href=&quot;https://zenodo.org/record/3069619/files/article.pdf&quot;&gt;editorial&lt;/a&gt; if you want to
know more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://rescience.github.io/news/2019/05/23/Redesign.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rescience.github.io/news/2019/05/23/Redesign.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sustainable computational science: the ReScience initiative</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We just published our white paper on ReScience in
&lt;a href=&quot;https://peerj.com/articles/cs-142/&quot;&gt;PeerJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Computer science offers a large set of tools for
prototyping, writing, running, testing, validating, sharing and reproducing
results; however, computational science lags behind. In the best case, authors
may provide their source code as a compressed archive and they may feel
confident their research is reproducible. But this is not exactly true. James
Buckheit and David Donoho proposed more than two decades ago that an article
about computational results is advertising, not scholarship. The actual
scholarship is the full software environment, code, and data that produced the
result. This implies new workflows, in particular in peer-reviews. Existing
journals have been slow to adapt: source codes are rarely requested and are
hardly ever actually executed to check that they produce the results advertised
in the article. ReScience is a peer-reviewed journal that targets computational
research and encourages the explicit replication of already published research,
promoting new and open-source implementations in order to ensure that the
original research can be replicated from its description. To achieve this goal,
the whole publishing chain is radically different from other traditional
scientific journals. ReScience resides on GitHub where each new implementation
of a computational study is made available together with comments,
explanations, and software tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;: N.P. Rougier et al., (2017) &lt;strong&gt;Sustainable computational science: the
ReScience initiative&lt;/strong&gt;. PeerJ Computer Science 3:e142. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj-cs.142&quot;&gt;DOI
doi.org/10.7717/peerj-cs.142&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://rescience.github.io/news/2017/12/18/ReScience-arXiv.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rescience.github.io/news/2017/12/18/ReScience-arXiv.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Call for replication</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is now possible to suggest an article for a replication. Just
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ReScience/call-for-replication/issues/new&quot;&gt;open a new issue&lt;/a&gt; 
in the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ReScience/call-for-replication&quot;&gt;call for replication repository&lt;/a&gt;
and give the reference of the original article and possibly the reason you
would like to see this article replicated (please refrain from suggesting your
own work). Note that you’re also encouraged to register as a reviewer such that
you can review the replication you’ve been proposing if someone actually takes
up the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for some challenge, you can also look at the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ReScience/call-for-replication/issues&quot;&gt;current list of suggestions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://rescience.github.io/news/2016/10/19/Call-For-Replication.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rescience.github.io/news/2016/10/19/Call-For-Replication.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You can help by becoming a reviewer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;ReScience is slowly gaining momentum and we currently have 4 submissions to
review. If you’re interested in helping ReScience and reproducibility, you can
become a reviewer. What you need is a github account, a one line description of
your expertise (see the &lt;a href=&quot;http://rescience.github.io/board/&quot;&gt;Board&lt;/a&gt; for some
examples) and to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ReScience/ReScience/issues/27&quot;&gt;tell us&lt;/a&gt; you’re interested such that we can add you to the board. You can also &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ReScience/ReScience-submission/subscription&quot;&gt;follow&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ReScience/ReScience-submission&quot;&gt;submission&lt;/a&gt; repository and propose your help whenever a submission falls into your expertise domain.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://rescience.github.io/news/2016/07/02/Reviewers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rescience.github.io/news/2016/07/02/Reviewers.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New year, new challenges ahead</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though open and reproducible science is gaining fast ground, there still
exists a large number of published computational researches that are just
awaiting replication. Why not pick your favorite paper and try to replicate it
? If you’re interested in this specific paper, chances are that your replication
will also be interesting for a lot of researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://rescience.github.io/news/2016/01/07/NewYear.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rescience.github.io/news/2016/01/07/NewYear.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ReScience: A Scientific Journal Living on Github</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.labcritics.com&quot;&gt;LabCritics&lt;/a&gt; kindly made a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.labcritics.com/rescience-a-scientific-journal-with-github-at-its-core-4729/?utm_source=@labcritics&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; introducing Re&lt;strong&gt;Science&lt;/strong&gt; and explaining its goals: “Computational research is set to get new open source journal solely for publishing implementations of algorithms and codes already published. Termed ReScience (Replicated Science – I guess [&lt;strong&gt;note&lt;/strong&gt;: yes]), the journal uses and exists solely on Github, a popular Web-based Git repository service, offering all of the distributed revision control and source code management functionality of Git.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://rescience.github.io/news/2015/09/06/LabCritics.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rescience.github.io/news/2015/09/06/LabCritics.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Official creation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s our great pleasure to announce the creation of Re&lt;strong&gt;Science&lt;/strong&gt; which is a
peer-reviewed journal that targets computational research and encourages the
explicit replication of already published research, promoting new and
open-source implementations in order to ensure that the original research is
reproducible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://rescience.github.io/news/2015/09/01/journal-start.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rescience.github.io/news/2015/09/01/journal-start.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review process test is over</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve been testing the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ReScience/ReScience-submission/pull/3&quot;&gt;review process&lt;/a&gt; with
Tiziano Zito (editor), Benoît Girard (reviewer) and Mehdi Khamassi
(reviewer). They helped smoothing the whole process and we’re ready for mass
production! But let’s wait for a second review…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://rescience.github.io/news/2015/08/10/ReviewTest.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rescience.github.io/news/2015/08/10/ReviewTest.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
